# NICOLÁS AYOBI MENDOZA

@ n.ayobi@uniandes.edu.co

**(**+57) 318 391 8489

% nayobi.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/nicolás-ayobi-mendoza-5b78141b1

Scholar.google.com/citations?user=YpUSLocAAAAJ&hl=es
 Scholar.google.com/citations.google.co

### **SUMMARY**

I am a resourceful and quick-learning first-year biomedical engineering master's student. I just finished my Bachelor's studies in biomédical engineering, with a double minor in Computational Mathematics and Bioinformatics. Additionally, I work as a graduate research assistant at the CinfonIA research center of the University of Los Andes on several projects focused on computer vision. My goal is to achieve a Ph.D. in the future to fully develop my research on machine vision applications in medicine. I aim to someday work in an extensive research center of applied artificial intelligence in the far future.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's degree: Biomedical Engineering

Universidad de Los Andes

🛗 Jan 2022 - Present

♥ Bogotá, Colombia

- Research master's focused on computer vision and Al.
- GPA: 4.75/5.0

Bachelor's degree: Biomedical Engineering Universidad de Los Andes

# Aug 2017 - Dec 2021

P Bogotá, Colombia

- Double Minor: Computational Mathematics & Bioinformatics
- GPA: 4.54/5.0

Undergraduate Exchange Program: Engineering

**University of New South Wales** 

**Aug** 2019 - Dec 2019

Sydney, Australia

### **EXPERIENCE**

Research Assistant: Computer Vision and Al CinfonlA, Universidad de Los Andes

Aug 2020 - Present

♥ Bogotá, Colombia

CinofnIA is the leading research center in artificial intelligence in Latin America.

- Work on multiple computer vision projects on natural and medical images.
- Implement state-of-the-art deep learning techniques and present results weekly.
- Process and analyze data gathered from different sources.

# Graduate Teaching Assistant: Computer Vision Course Universidad de Los Andes

🛗 Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

- ♥ Bogotá, Colombia
- Proposed and evaluated laboratory assignments about different computer vision models and tasks.
- Formulated and graded theoretical and practical exams.
- Assisted students with their research projects for the course.
- Created contents for the new Coursera's Master's degree in Al.

# Undergraduate Teaching Assistant: Multiple Courses Universidad de Los Andes

math Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

- P Bogotá, Colombia
- Helped the teachers with course planning.
- Created practical workshops and assisted students during their laboratories and course projects.
- Graded some of the research projects and practical assignments developed in the courses.

#### Courses:

- Coursera's Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence  $\sim$  Oct 2021 Dec 2021
- Introduction to Programming  $\sim$  Aug 2021 Dec 2021
- Data Structures and Algorithms  $\sim$  Jan 2021 Jun 2021
- **Data Structures**  $\sim$  Aug 2020 Jun 2021
- Image Analysis and Processing  $\sim$  Aug 2020 Dec 2020
- Biomedical Engineering Foundations of Neurosurgery  $\sim$  Jan 2020 Jun 2020

## **RESEARCH PROJECTS**

- Visual Grounding (Vision & Language):
   Collaboration with Google Research Zurich to create visual grounding benchmarks with high granularity in vision and language.
- Robot-Assisted Surgical Scene Understanding: Implementation of video analysis methods for multitask surgical workflow analysis on robot-assisted surgery videos.
- Surgical Risk Prediction:
   Applying deep regression algorithms to predict risk probabilities based on personalized patient variables.
- Robust 3D Medical Image Recognition:
  Use of robust 3D deep learning techniques for knee injury identification on a small amount of MRIs.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Panoptic Narrative Grounding. C. González, N. Ayobi, I. Hernández, J. Hernández, J. Pont-Tuset, P. Arbeláez. Oral Presentation at ICCV 2021.
- 2. Towards Holistic Surgical Scene Understanding. N. Valderrama, P.Ruiz, I. Hernandez, N. Ayobi, M. Verlyk, J. Santander, J. Caicedo, N. Fernandez, P. Arbeláez. Oral Presentation at MICCAI 2022.
- 3. Development of a Mobile App for Preoperative Evaluation of Sinus CT Scan: One Step Towards Artificial Intelligence. J. Ospina, C. Forigua, A. Hernandez, N. Ayobi, T. Correa. Journal Paper in Acta de Otorrinolaringología & Cirugía de Cabeza y Cuello.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

Python, Pytorch
Matlab, Java, Bash, ŁTŁX
HTML, Docker
C++, SQL, Tensorflow



Languages

Spanish (Native), English (C1)

Soft Skills

Self-taught, Quick Learner, Resourcefulness, Multi-Tasking, Teamwork, Persistence, Leadership

## **HONOURS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner of the 2022 Instrumentation Segmentation and Action Recognition in Robot-Assisted Radical Prostatectomies Challenge (SAR-RARP50)

**♥** MICCAI 2022, Singapore

Winner of a sub-challenge of the Endoscopic Vision Grand Challenge in MICCAI 2022

**Cum Laude Bachelor's Graduation Honour** 

# Apr 2022

♥ Bogotá, Colombia

## DeepMind-CinfonIA Master's Scholarship

🛗 Jan 2022 - Present

P Bogotá, Colombia

DeepMind's Scholarship Program for complete master's degree coverage.

#### **Uniandinos Excellence Scholarship**

🛗 Jul 2019 - June 2021

♥ Bogotá, Colombia

50% tuition scholarship awarded to outstanding students with the highest GPAs.

#### Biomedical Engineering Top 10 GPAs Award

🛗 Jun 2020 - Present

♥ Bogotá, Colombia

Award given biannually to the best 10 GPAs in the biomedical engineering department.